<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>ntumbuka[sic]</title><subtitle>After being harrassed by [some guy](https://github.com/zikani03) for nearly half a decade to start a blog, I decided to start a blog. Pretty much what you get here are my thoughts on various topics. The goal isn't to educate, I simply need a space to help me organise my thoughts but you might find it useful.</subtitle> <updated>2024-05-22T16:57:26+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2024 Walter Kaunda </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Kugwidwa Ufiti in a Serverless Database</title><link href="/posts/kugwira-mfiti-in-a-serverless-database/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kugwidwa Ufiti in a Serverless Database" /><published>2024-05-21T18:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2024-05-22T16:56:43+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/kugwira-mfiti-in-a-serverless-database/</id> <content src="/posts/kugwira-mfiti-in-a-serverless-database/" /> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> </author> <category term="Databases" /> <category term="Data Engineering" /> <summary> In late 2022, we started exploring Snowflake as an alternative to our existing data warehouse solution at my usual place of work. Before then we were a strictly Microsoft SQL server house. Sequel Server was adopted in the first place because the organisation already had a lot of expertise around it. Adopting it as a data warehouse was rather natural. It did serve the organisation quite well for... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>My First AOC Experience [DRAFT]</title><link href="/posts/my-first-aoc-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First AOC Experience [DRAFT]" /><published>2024-01-09T12:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2024-01-09T21:43:25+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/my-first-aoc-experience/</id> <content src="/posts/my-first-aoc-experience/" /> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> Last year I decided to try out Advent of Code (AOC). I didn’t get to finish the whole thing. From what I managed to do though, I had fun and I believe that I levelled up a bit in the language I used. My initial goals for AOC 2023 were to build more familiarity with two languages: Crystal and Scala. Crystal because that is what I have decided to make as my language of choice for any personal ex... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Don't Settle Too Early [DRAFT]</title><link href="/posts/dont-settle-too-early/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't Settle Too Early [DRAFT]" /><published>2023-11-08T20:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2024-01-10T23:37:15+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/dont-settle-too-early/</id> <content src="/posts/dont-settle-too-early/" /> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> A couple of days ago there was a debate on programming languages (technology in general). in one of our local developer groups. The initial proposition that was made was kind of something like PHP is a dead language. Everyone should switch to Python instead, well … because AI (I don’t agree with 99% of the arguments that were made in support of this, story for another day though…). The debate p... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>A Case for Paper Based Workflows</title><link href="/posts/A-Case-For-File-Based-Workflows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Case for Paper Based Workflows" /><published>2023-10-19T20:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-10-19T20:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/A-Case-For-File-Based-Workflows/</id> <content src="/posts/A-Case-For-File-Based-Workflows/" /> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> A common thread I find in most software developers’ product pitches in Malawi (Africa as a whole too to some extent) revolves around replacing paper based workflows with almost one hundred percent digital workflows. Complete elimination of paper in any workflow is seen as a big plus. Whilst I do understand where this line of thinking is coming from, I find that more often than not these product... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I Hate File System Based Routing</title><link href="/posts/I-Hate-File-System-Based-Routing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Hate File System Based Routing" /><published>2023-07-30T23:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-07-30T23:04:31+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/I-Hate-File-System-Based-Routing/</id> <content src="/posts/I-Hate-File-System-Based-Routing/" /> <author> <name>Walter Kaunda</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> I have been using Sveltekit on a number of projects for a while now. Whilst I like some of its ideas, there is one thing that just undoes the whole thing for me. File system based routing, it sounds like a good idea but in practice it’s annoying as f%$k on any moderately complex application. It pretty much breaks how I work with any of my text editors of choice (neovim / vscode). First problem... </summary> </entry> </feed>
